Finding Aid for Solomon Jacob Axelrod papers, 1934-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Solomon Jacob Axelrod papers
1934-1988
Axelrod, Solomon Jacob, 1912-1987.
921079 Aa 2
Public health physician, specialist in public health economics, professor in the University of Michigan School of Public Health, director of its Bureau of Public Health Economics, and chairman of the Department of Medical Care Organization. Personal materials, correspondence, topical files, academic materials, and audio tapes relating to his professional and academic career.
19.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Axelrod Collection (donor no. 7535 ) was the gift of Mrs. Solomon Axelrod. The collection came to the library in several accessions, 1988-1991.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Solomon Jacob Axelrod was born in Gloversville, New York on September 25, 1912. He graduated Phi Beta Kappa from Dartmouth College in 1934 and received his MD from Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia in 1938. After his internship at the Indigents Clinic of Philadelphia General Hospital, Axelrod became a research fellow in venereal disease control at the University of Pennsylvania.
In 1941 Axelrod became a medical officer for the Tennessee State Department of Health where he worked on controlling venereal disease and tuberculosis. From 1943 to 1949 Axelrod worked as a commissioned officer in the United States Public Health Service (PHS), first as a venereal disease control officer, then in the migrant labor health program, and lastly as a rural health consultant. In this latter position he was assigned to the State of Michigan, where he used the occasion to continue his studies at the University of Michigan. Axelrod completed his master's degree in public health in 1948 and then went on to become Medical Director of the Michigan Rapid Treatment Center located in Ann Arbor.
The development of antibiotics to treat syphilis about this time soon made rapid treatment centers obsolete, so Axelrod faced reassignment by the PHS. He had to make a decision in 1949 when he was requested to return to Washington D.C. to help implement the national health insurance program which was expected to be enacted under the Truman Administration. Nathan Sinai, Director of the Bureau of Public Health Economics at UM, convinced Axelrod to resign his commission in PHS and become a faculty member of the UM School of Public Health, an affiliation he maintained until his retirement in 1977.
In 1959 Axelrod succeeded Sinai as Director of the Bureau of Public Health Economics, and from 1965 to 1970 he served as the first Chairman of UM's Department of Medical Care Organization, a unit that Axelrod had himself founded.
Throughout his distinguished career, Axelrod held various appointments with local, state, national, and international organizations, including the Governor's Public Health Study Commission (Michigan), the Pan American Health Organization, the National Institute of Rehabilitation, and the American Public Health Association. In addition, Axelrod worked with the United Auto Workers to promote the establishment of health maintenance organizations, and was a founding member of the Committee for National Health Insurance.
In 1978, Axelrod retired from the University but continued to be active professionally. Locally, he helped establish a Medicare counseling program within the Washtenaw County Council on Aging. Among his other projects was his work to devise and implement a program to restrain health care costs in Michigan. He also worked with Comprehensive Health Services of Detroit, a health maintenance organization serving the largely low income population of the inner city.
Solomon Axelrod died September 21, 1987.
The papers of Solomon J. Axelrod came to the Bentley Library in four major accessions: 1988, 1990, 1991 and 1996. Each of these accessions were processed separately by different individuals. In 2008 the materials were re-processed and the different accessions were interfiled.
Axelrod's collection is divided into six series: Personal Materials, Topical / Organizational Files, Academic Materials, Correspondence, Farm Labor Health Program, and Audio Materials.
Subjects:
Axelrod, Solomon J. (Solomon Jacob), 1912-1987; Committee for National Health Insurance (U.S.); Community Research Associates.; National Health Assembly (1948: Washington, D.C.); Public health--United States.; University of Michigan. Bureau of Public Health Economics.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Medical Care Organization.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Public Health.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Axelrod, Solomon J. (Solomon Jacob), 1912-1987; Insurance, Health.; Medical care.
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.
- Personal Materials, 1942-1988
  The Personal Materials series (0.75 linear feet) consists of biographical data, papers presented, speeches, and files relating to various studies that he undertook in the 1950s. Of immediate interest to the researcher will be the folder of biographical material containing oral history and other interviews with Axelrod. The speeches folders document the broad range of Axelrod's interests.
  - Appointments and Committees, 1972-1985 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1961-1972
    - "Alternatives for Financing HMO's,", 1972 (Box 1)
    - "Background Paper on the Issue of Public Support for the Michigan College of Osteopathic Medicine" (draft), 1968 (Box 1)
    - "A Critique of Ameriplan," (roundtable), 1971 (Box 1)
    - "The Evaluation of Old Age Assistance Medical Care Programs,", 1961 (Box 1)
    - "Organizing Medical Care Programs to Meet Health Needs,", 1961 (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1969-1985
    - Black Caucus of Health Workers Award, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Distinguished Achievement Award, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1985 (scattered), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Biographical, 1967-1988; 3 folders (Box 1)
    (include photograph)
  - Condolences, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1974 (Box 1)
  - Oral History, American Hospital Association, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Reports, 1971-1984
    - "Medical Care Cost Containment in Workers' Compensation in Michigan,", 1984 (Box 1)
    - "Proposed Graduate Program in Community Health: Report of a Site Visit ", November 25-26, 1975; December 1975 (Box 1)
    - "The Use of Fiscal Agents in Medicaid,", 1971 (Box 1)
  - Retirement, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1966-1985 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1942-1984
    - Community Research Associates, San Mateo, 1954 (Box 1)
    - "Consumer Participation in Administration of Health Services,", 1973 (Box 1)
    - "The Crisis in Health Care,", 1973 (Box 1)
    - Economic Factors-Medical Decisions, October 1984 (Box 1)
    - Fifty Years of Teaching Medical Care Organization, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Medical Care (Box 1)
    - "Medicare and Medical Care,", 1967 (Box 1)
    - "Problems faced by Prepaid Dental Plans,", 1955 (Box 1)
    - Rural Health Services, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Self Care Conference, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Tuberculosis, undated, 1942-1943 (Box 1)
    - Venereal Disease undated, 1943 (includes radio talks) (Box 1)
  - Studies, 1955-1959
    - Branch and Hillsdale County Hospital Project (includes report), 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - Pan American Sanitary Bureau, undated; 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - "Study on Windsor Physicians." (includes survey), 1956 (Box 1)
    - World Health Organization, undated; 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Summaries of Activities, 1964; 1971-1973 (Box 1)
- Topical / Organizational Files
  The Topical / Organizational Files series (8.25 linear feet), arranged alphabetically by subject or the name of an organization, consists of materials related to Axelrod's interest and activities in a number of public health planning councils, committees, and task force groups, as well as correspondence, notes, and related materials. Folders pertaining to the School of Public Health document Axelrod's teaching career. "Rural Health Services" and "Community Research Associates" document Axelrod's concerns for the health care of farmers and migrants during the Great Depression and the displaced persons of Europe following World War II. Also included are reports and memos on legislative bills affecting the public health care system in the United States. Other documentation includes Awards and Honors, "Background Paper on the Michigan College for Osteopathic Medicine," Bibliographical Material, Michigan Office of Services to the Aging and Oral History of the American Hospital Association.
  - American Association of Public Health Physicians-Minutes, 4/10/1968 (Box 1)
  - American Board of Preventive Medicine & Public Health Inc., 1945-1950 (Box 1)
  - American Hospital Association, 1979 (Box 1)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association (AMA) Council on Medical Services, 1947 (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Association (APHA), 1948-1968
    - "Attitudes of Subscribers Towards Comprehensive Physicians Insurance,", 1955 (Box 1)
    - "Health Problems in Industrialized Agriculture,", 1948 (Box 1)
    - Joint Committee-APHA and APWA, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - General, 1949; 1968 (Box 1)
  - American Public Welfare Association (APWA)-Medical Assistance Research Project, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Arizona State University, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Association of Business Management in Public Health, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Association of Schools of Public Health-Special Committee on Medical Care, 1946-1967 (Box 1)
  - Association of University Programs in Hospital Administration-Constitution and Bylaws, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Bureau of Public Health Economics, undated; 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Paper-Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Capital Expenditure Cap, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Certificate of Need (CON), 1983 (Box 2)
  - Commission on Chronic Illness, 1950-1954; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Commission on Financing of Hospital Care, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
  - Commission on Migratory Labor, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Committee for National Health Insurance (CNHI), 1971-1980
    - Costs and Financing, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - "The Costs of a National Health Security Program and Their Financing," (report), 1971 (Box 2)
    - General, 1975-1980; 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Kennedy Bills, 1971-1979; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Long-Ribicoff Bill, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Mental Health, 1971-1972; 1975 (Box 2)
    - Presidential Health Messages, 1973-1978 (Box 2)
  - Committee for a National Health Service, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Community Research Associates, 1950-1955
    - Background Material, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Budget and Project Requests, 1953-1955 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955
      - Buell, Bradley, 1954 (Box 2)
      - General (includes some minutes), 1954-1955 (Box 2)
      - Hatcher, Dr. Gordon, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - Distribution Report, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - Hagerstown, Mary, 1951-1955
      - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
      - Notebook, 1954 (Box 2)
      - Reports, undated; 1954 (Box 2)
      - "Some Conditions Leading to Medical Dependency in Hagerstown, Md." by P.S. Lawrence, Sc.D., 1951 (Box 2)
    - Headquarters Board Minutes, undated; 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 1950-1955 (Box 2)
    - Operational Manual, undated; 1954 (Box 3)
    - Personnel, 1954-1955
      - Medical Social Workers, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
      - Research Directors, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
    - Proposals for Community Rates, 1952-1954 (Box 3)
    - San Mateo, 1953-1954
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1953-1954 (Box 3)
      - Notebook, 1954 (Box 3)
      - Operation Manual, 1954 (Box 3)
      - Reports, 1954 (Box 3)
    - Statistical Guide, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
    - Winona, Minnesota, 1952-1954
      - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
      - Department of Health-Annual Report, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 3)
      - Notebook, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Statistics, 1954 (Box 3)
      - Community Problems Handbook, November 1953; 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - Comprehensive Health Planning Council of Sea Mic, 1979-1986
    - "Criteria and Standards for Home Health Care in Southeastern Michigan,", 1979 (Box 3)
    - Huron Valley Hospital, 1984; 1986 (Box 3)
    - "Study and Recommendations of the Home Health Care Technical Advisory Panel,", 1979 (Box 3)
  - Comprehensive Health Planning Council of Whatcom, Skagit, Island, and San Juan Counties (Washington State)
    - Home Health Services Reports, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Home Health Services Development Guide,", 1975 (Box 3)
    - Home Health Services Survey,", 1975 (Box 3)
    - Home Health Services Under Medicare and Medicaid: A Critical Analysis,", 1975 (Box 3)
  - Comprehensive Health Services of Detroit (CHSD), 1970-1987
    - Annual Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 3)
    - Background Materials, 1972; 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - Committees, 1980; 1987 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, undated; 1970; 1976; 1978-1981 (Box 3)
    - Management Organization Study, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - Proposed CHSD Hospital Reporting System, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Conference on the Teaching of Medical Care, 1952-1966
    - General, 1957; 1964-1966 (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1952; 1965 (Box 3)
  - Cooperative Health Federation of America, 1948; 1957; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center-Regionalization, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Democratic Party Task Force on Health, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Detroit Health Department-Family Oriented Primary Care Task Force (East Side Health Center), 1978-1980; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Detroit Mayor's Committees, 1969-1972
    - Comprehensive Health Care Subcommittee, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
    - Mayor's Committee to Study Medical Care of the Indigent and Medically Indigent and Hospital Emergency Care, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Mayor's Health Care Advisory Commission, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
    - New City Charter, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Economic Alliance for Michigan, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Gary Methodist Lawsuit, 1975-1978
    - Background, 1975; 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Draft Regional Plan, 1975 (Box 4)
    - Exhibits, 1974; 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Legal Documents, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - GINI Associates (consultants), 1986 (Box 4)
  - Governor's Special Counselor on Workers' Compensation, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Gray Panthers, 1981-1984 (Box 4)
  - Health Aspects of the Economics of Aging-Report, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Health Insurance, Private and Mental Health, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Health Maintenance Organizations (HMO's), 1977; 1979-1981 (Box 4)
  - Incentive Reimbursement Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Institute of Gerontology, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, 1959-1965 (Box 4)
  - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals, 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Joint Committee on Medical Care Teaching, 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Kiddicare, 1972; 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Marion Co (Indiana) Health Department-Administrative Retreat, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Mayor's Committee on Medical Care, 1966-1969; 16 folders (Box 5)
  - Medicaid Project, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
  - Medical Advisory Committee, 1965-1969 (Box 5)
  - Medical Care Advisory Council-Ad Hoc Committee on Planning, 1979; 1981-1983 (Box 5)
  - Medical Care Journal, 1966-1969; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Michigan Medicaid Task Force, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Office of Services to the Aging, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Welfare League, 1951; 1956 (Box 5)
  - Migrant Health Project Review Committee, 1969-1971; 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Minnesota Health Security Action Council, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Model Cities Program-Ann Arbor, 1970; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Montefiore Home Care (home health care in New York State), 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Montefiore Training Program for Medical Care Administration, 1970 (Box 5)
  - National Association of Colored Nurses, 1946 (Box 5)
  - National Health Assembly, 1948-1949
    - Addresses, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Agendas, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Committee of Physicians For the Improvement of Medical Care, Inc.-Report, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
    - Delegate Lists, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Digest of Proceedings, May 1948; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Medical Care Section-Report, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Photograph, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Professional Personnel Section-Physicians and Related Data (includes graphs and support materials), May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Rural Health Section-Recommendations and Reports, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Section on State and Community Planning for Health, May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Section Reports and Recommendations (various), May 1948 (Box 6)
    - Subcommittee Reports and Recommendations, May 1948 (Box 6)
  - National Institute on Rehabilitation and Labor Health Services
    - 1959-1963 (Box 6)
    - 1964, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - 1965, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - 1966, 7 folders (Box 6)
    - 1967, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Demonstration Project, 1960-1962 (Box 6)
    - General, 1959-1963; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Regional Institutes, 1960-1962 (Box 7)
    - Workshops, 1960-1963 (Box 7)
  - New Detroit-Health Committee
    - 1968-1977, 24 folders (Box 7)
    - Working Paper (D.A.T.A) (Box 7)
  - New Detroit, Inc., 1972 (Box 7)
  - New England Hospital Assembly, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper Columns-Detroit Free Press and Ann Arbor News, 1983; 1986-1987 (Box 7)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1967-1971; 5 folders (Box 7)
  - New York Foundation, 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - Niagara Falls Academy of Medicine, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Nursing Home Reimbursement Task Force, 1982-1983; 6 folders (Box 7)
  - Oakwood Hospital Classes, 1984-1985
    - Background Materials, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Case Studies., undated (Box 7)
    - General, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Lecture Notes, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Office of Services to the Aging, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
  - Pan American Health Organization, 1970-1973
    - Data and Notes, 1971-1973 (Box 8)
    - Diary, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - "Ministerio de Salud. Zona de Salud Metropolitana Lima-Callao Area Hospitalaria No. 6. Descripcin de la situacion de Salud e instrumentacion, Ano 1971. Programacin de las actividades de Salud para el Ao 1973" (Spanish), 1972 (Box 8)
  - People's Republic of China, 1976-1980
    - "Clinical Practice and Public Health," study by Myron E. Wegman, 1978 (Box 8)
    - "Health Care and The People's Republic of China"-Group Journal, 1979 (Box 8)
    - "Journal of a Trip to China August 17-September 6, 1977" by Deborah Oakley, 1977 (Box 8)
    - "Log-People's Republic of China. Visit by Sarah & Philip Power ", February 10-27, 1976; 1976 (Box 8)
    - "Political Process and the Integration of Traditional and Western Medicine in the PRC" by Marilynn M. Rosenthal, 1980 (Box 8)
  - The Physicians Forum, Inc., 1946-1957
    - Correspondence, 1947-1952; 1955-1956 (Box 8)
    - Minutes, Constitution and Bylaws, undated; 1947-1950 (Box 8)
    - Publications, undated; 1946-1957 (scattered) (Box 8)
  - Poverty and Human Resources Abstract, 1966-1971 (Box 8)
  - President's Commission on Health, 1952; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Puerto Rico, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Reorganization Task Force
    - April-May 1967 (Box 8)
    - June 1967, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - July 1967 (Box 8)
  - Resident County Hospitalization Project, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Rural Health Services, 1938-1949
    - American-Soviet Medical Society, 1946 (Box 8)
    - California Farm Reporter, December 1947-May 1948 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 8)
    - Council for Social Action Congregational Christian Churches, 1947 (Box 8)
    - Expenditures, 1946-1947 (Box 8)
    - Farm Organizations, undated; 1938-1948 (Box 8)
    - Farm Security Administration, 1945 (Box 8)
    - Food, Tobacco, Agricultural and Allied Union of America-Importation of Agricultural Labor, 1948 (Box 8)
    - Home Missions, 1947-1949 (Box 8)
    - Institute of Ethnic Affairs-"A Proposal Concerning the Spanish Speaking People in the United States,", undated (Box 8)
    - Interstate Conference on Migratory Farm Labor-Report, 1947 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Rural Health Conference, August 1948 (Box 8)
    - National Citizens Council for Migrant Labor (includes notebook), 1947-1949 (Box 8)
    - National Farmers Union, 1945-1948 (Box 8)
    - National Grange, 1943-1948 (Box 8)
    - National Sharecroppers Fund, 1947 (Box 8)
    - Tuberculosis Control-Chattanooga, Tennessee undated, 1942-1943 (includes lecture notes) (Box 8)
  - St. Joseph Mercy Hospital, 1970-1975; 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Senior Spectrum (radio program), 1986 (Box 9)
  - Staffing, 1978; 1981 (Box 9)
  - State Health Planning Advisory Council-Task Force on Long-Term Care, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Student American Medical Association, 1969; 1975 (Box 9)
  - Union Health Service, Inc., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Unitarian Service Committee, 1947-1948
    - Border Trends: A Monthly Summary of Significant Events Pertaining to Anglo-Latin Relations in Texas, 1948 (Box 9)
    - Texas Migrant Project, 1947-1948 (Box 9)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1942-1948
    - Extension Service, 1947-1948 (Box 9)
    - Inter-Bureau Committee on Post-War Programs, undated; 1945 (Box 9)
    - Office of Labor, 1944-1947
      - Directories and Organizational Charts, undated; 1944-1947 (Box 9)
      - Health Services Branch-Reports to the Surgeon General, 1945-1947 (Box 9)
    - Office of Rural Health Services, 1942-1946 (Box 9)
    - "Use of Medical Services in Rural Missouri,", 1946 (Box 9)
    - Venereal Disease Control, undated; 1940-1951 (Box 9)
  - United States Department of Agriculture-Labor Branch-Notebook, 1945 (Box 9)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
    - Appalachian Task Force, 1976-1978
      - Background, undated; 1976-1977 (Box 9)
      - General, 1977-1978; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Health Services Organization Branch, Division of Medical Care Administration-Staff Orientation (transcripts of presentation), 1968 (Box 9)
  - University of Alabama in Birmingham-Department of Public Health, 1974; 1980 (Box 9)
  - Working Conditions, 1978; 1980 (Box 9)
  - Workmen's Compensation, 1957-1976; 1982-1985; 2 folders (Box 9)
- Academic Materials
  The Academic Materials series (4.5 linear feet) contains mostly lecture notes which explore the topics of public health insurance and other tax-supported medical programs and services as well as materials generated by Axelrod in his teaching and administrative positions at the University of Michigan and the UM School of Public Health. Much of the School of Public Health material consists of written surveys and research proposals conducted by the Bureau of Public Health Economics during Axelrod's tenure as the director. There are also materials relating to Axelrod's committee work on the Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA), including minutes and reports from various sub-committees. Also included in this series are materials that document Axelrod's activities as a visiting professor at the University of California at Irving, his work at the Cornell Institute, and Medicare Talks. Other file headings include Aging, Correspondence, Reports on Community Medicine, and Veteran's Administration.
  - Blue Cross
    - National Executive Training Program, 1952-1955; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Program Materials
      - Advanced Course, 1953; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Beginning Course, 1953-1955; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Class Materials
    - Public Health 120, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - Public Health 138, undated (Box 10)
    - Public Health 201, University of Penn. Course, undated (Box 10)
    - Public Health 201, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Public Health Planning 202, undated (Box 10)
    - Public Health 203, 1955 (Box 10)
    - Social Work 140, 1951-1952; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Cornell Institute, 1967-1982; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Course Planning, 1956-1967
    - C.H.S. 630-631, undated; 1961-1966 (Box 10)
    - General, undated; 1956-1965 (Box 10)